Guide to the Waldemar H. Fries Audubon research papers, 1805-1980.
Fries, Waldemar H., Audubon research papers
- Series XII. Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence and Forms: Veterans Administration, 1919, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 81)
Life and Adventures of Audubon the Naturalist; By Robert Buchanan, Introduction by John Burroughs by Audubon, John James
Published: London, J.M. Dent and Sons, and New York, E.P. Dutton and Co. [Everymans Library]
Notes by Fries: Ex libris card. Inserted loose copy of pg 24 of the book
Life of john James Audubon, the naturalist. With an introduction by John Burroughs by Audubon, John James
Published: London, J.M. Dent and Sons, and New York, E.P. Dutton and Co. [Everymans Library]
Notes by Fries: Previous owner bill and ex libris card. Inserted, loose note.
Ornithological Biography; or, An account of the habits of the birds of the united States of America; accompanied by descriptions of the objects represented in the work entitled The Birds of America and interspersed with delineations of American scenery and manners. by Audubon, John James
Published: Edinburgh, A. Black, 1831-1849 [i.e. 1839]
Notes by Fries: vol1 (1831) has a typewritten plate on the cover, vol 2 (1834) has inserted newspaper clippings, vol 3( 1835) nothing; vol 4 (1838) has copies of articles stapled or inserted, v 5 (1849) has an inserted loose copy of an Audubon letter; All of the above rebound by Fries, missing pages inserted; and include common names of birds, plate numbers, dates noted in ink or pencil, scattered through books.
The Nucleus of a Library; a study of the book collection of the University of michigan and the personalities involved in its acquisition, 1837-1845 by Bidlack, Russell Eugene
Published: Ann Arbor, Mich., University of Michigan, Department of Library Science, 1962
Notes by Fries: Notes on cover; signed by the author to Fries
The Athenaeum Centenary. The influence and history of the Boston Athenaeum from 1807-1907 by Boston Athenaeum
Published: Boston, The Boston Athenaeum, 1907
Notes by Fries: Note on page 174.
Audubon by Bradford, Mary Flucker
Published: New Orleans, Press of L. Graham and Son Ltd., 1897
Notes by Fries: Note inside front cover :"See pg41". Ex libris card
Edward Harris, Friend fo Audubon by Brannon, Peter Alexander
Published: New York, Newcomen Socity of England, American branch, 1947
Notes by Fries: 1st Copy: None. 2nd Copy: notes in margins of multiple pages
Lives of Labour; or, Incidents in the carees of eminent naturalists and celebrated travellers by Brightwell, Cecilia Lucy
Published: London, New York, etc., T. Nelson, 1874
Notes by Fries: Citation on front cover "Thomas I White, First Class Prize…. 1875". Includes a note from Fries referencing Audubon pg. nos in book
The World of Washington Irving by Brooks, Van Wyck
Published: New York, E.P. Dutton and Co., 1944
Notes by Fries: None. Ex libris card
John James Audubon by Burroughs, John
Published: Boston, Small, Maynard and Company, 1902
Notes by Fries: Large paper copy (edition lmiited to 350 copies) includes Copies of reviews and author bio. Ex libris Card 2nd copy is a small trade copy, includes name of previous owner in ink, and part of a chapter from "Birds of America" in the form of a pasted book inside front cover, with inscription, possibly from John P. Wetherell (pg 2. of accension folder).
In the Days of Audubon; a tale of the 'protector of birds', with an appendix on the formation of Audubon Societies. Illustrated by B. West Clinedinst and others. by Butterworth, Hezekiah
Published: New York, D. Appleton and Company, 1901
Notes by Fries: None. 1st includes copies of the cover page, 2nd includes previous owner name in ink.
Alexander Wilson; Naturalist and pioneer, a biography. With decorations by Robert Ball by Cantwell, Robert
Published: Philadelphia, Lippincott, 1961
Notes by Fries: Inserted book review; note "valley?" on pg 298.
Simple Love and Occasional Pieces in Verse, with a notice of Audubon by Claiborne, Fernand
Published: New Orleans La., J.G. Hauser, "The Legal Printer", 1906
Notes by Fries: None. Bound with string.
Minds of Men, Vol II: Search for Publication by Clark, Byron H
Published: Dayton, OH, Mead Corporation, 1966
Notes by Fries: inserted slip of notes. Packaging preserved
John James Audubon by Clark, Edward Brayton
Published: 19--?
Notes by Fries: inserted slip of notes.
A History of the Maryland State Library, 1827-1939 by Coover, Robert Wingert
Published: Rochester, NY, University of Rochester press, 1957
Notes by Fries: None. "Compliments of …." written in ink on first page
Miss Douglas of new York; a biography by Davidson, Angus
Published: New York, Viking Press, 1953
Notes by Fries: Notes on page 64. Ex libris card
National Potrait Gallery of Eminent Americans; including orators, satesmen, naval and military heroes, jurists, authors etc, from paintings by Alonzo Chappel. Vol II. by Duyckinck, Evert Augustus
Published: New York, Johnson, Fry and Co., 1862
Notes by Fries: None; (book dated 1872)
The Life of Audubon; with a foreword by John Kieran, Illustrated with paintings and drawings by John James Audubon from the permanent collection of the American Museum of Natural History by Fisher, Clyde
Published: New York, Harper, 1949
Notes by Fries: None. Ex libris card
Audubon's butterflies, moths and other studies. by Ford, Alice Elizabeth
Published: New York, Studio Publications in association with Cowell, 1952
Notes by Fries: Notes on page 78. Ex libris card
Mark Catesby; the Colonial Audubon, by Gerge Frederick Frick and Raymond Phineas Stearns by Frick, George Frederick
Published: Urbana, University of Illinois Press, 1961
Louis Agassiz Fuertes: his life briefly told and his correspondence edited by Mary Fuertes Boynton. by Fuertes, Louis Agassiz
Published: New York, Oxford University Press, 1956
Notes by Fries: Note on front cover "see page 199"
Commemorative addresses: George William Curtis, Edwin Booth, Louis Kossuth, John James Audubon, William Cullen Bryant by Godwin, Park
Published: New York, Harper, 1895
Notes by Fries: None. Second copy is photocopied.
Audubon Park: The History of the Site of the Hispanic Society of America and Neighbouring Institutions by Grineell, George Goldberg
Published: new York, Hispanic Society of America, 1927
Notes by Fries: Photocopied.
The Buffalo Public Library; Commemorating its first century of service to the citizens of Buffalo, 1836-1936 by Goldberg, Arthur
Published: Buffalo, NY, Privately printed, 1937
Thomas Nutall, naturalist; explorations in America, 1808-1841 by Graustein, Jeannette E.
Published: Cambridge, Harvard University Press, 1967
Notes by Fries: Loose inserted sheet of notes
The Christopher Happoldt Journal, his Europeamn Tour with the Rev. John Bachman (June-December 1838). Edited with preface and biographies by Claude Henry Nueffer by Happoldt, Christopher
Published: Charleston, S.C., Charleston Museum, 1960
Notes by Fries: None. Inserted book review/biography.
Up the Missouri with Audubon; the journal of Edward harris, edited by John Francis McDermott. by Harris, Edward
Published: Norman, Oklahoma, University of Oklahoma Press, 1951
Notes by Fries: None. Book bill and ex libris card
The Story of J.J. Audubon. Illustrated by Federico Castellon by Howard, Joan
Published: New York, Grosset and Dunlap, 1954
John Work Garret and his Library at Evergreen House by (John Work Garret)
Published: Baltimore, Privately printed by Schneidereith and Sons, 1944
Notes by Fries: Citation in ink: "For Dr. Buggles from Alice Garrett", notes on Audubon references on front cover
Audubon; Cultural graded Readers, French Series :1 (Elementary) by Keating, Clark and Moraud, Marcel I
Published: New York, American Book Co., 1958
Mr. Audubon's Lucy by Kennedy, Lucy
Published: New York, Crown Publishers, 195
Notes by Fries: 1st copy includes Citation in ink: "To Lucy Fries, ... the Elephant Hunter 1957"; 2nd copy: None.
John James Audubon, by Amrgaret Ford and John Keiran; illustrated by Christine Price. by Kieran, Margaret Ford
Published: New York, Random House, 1954
Notes by Fries: 1st copy: None. Includes date of purchase on loose card. 2nd Copy: None
Young Audubon, boy naturalist, illustrated by Will Forrest. by Mason, Miriam Evangeline
Published: Indianapolis, New York, The Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1943
Notes by Fries: None. Ex libris card
Audacious Audubon, the story of a great pioneer, artist, naturalist and man by Muschamp, Edward A.
Published: New York, Brentano's, 1929
Notes by Fries: Ex libris card. Note on front page "Reviewed in Auk….."; previous owner name in pencil
Die Illustruerten Vogelbucher, ihre Geschichte und Bibliographie by Nissen, Claus
Published: Stuttgart, Hiersmannm 1953
Notes by Fries: Icludes a letter,1967, on front page, and price list; Ex libris card
The Baltimore Oriole, and a biographical sketch of Audubon by Payne, Raphael Samuel
Published: Baltimore, The Norman, Remibngton Company, 1923
John James Audubon, his life. Illustrated by Margaret Ayer by Peare, Catherine Owens
Published: New York, Holt, 1953
Green Laurels; the lives and achievements of the great naturalists by Peattie, Donald Culross
Published: New York, The Literary Guild, 1936
Notes by Fries: Includes an inserted loose note, pg 232
Singing in the Wildreness; a salute to John James Audubon by
Published: New York, Putnam, 1935
Notes by Fries: None. Ex libris Card
Audubon's Adventures; or, Life in the Woods. by Peirce, Bradford Kinney
Published: New York, Hunt and Eaton; Cincinnati, Cranston and Stone, 1889
Notes by Fries: None. Previous owner name in pencil
Audubon In Florida, with selections from the writings of John James Audubon by Proby, Katherine Hall
Published: Coral Gables, Florida, University of Miami Press, 1974
Notes by Fries: Note from the author to Fries
Audubon. With 12 colored plates from original Audubon prints; black and white illustrations by James MacDonald by Rourke, Constance Mayfield
Published: New York, Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1936
Notes by Fries: Newspaoer clippings relating to book on front page, ex libris card
Joe Mason, apprentice to Audubon by Simon, Charlie May Hogue
Published: New York, Dutton, 1946
A Gentleman of the Old natchez Region, Benjamin L. C. Wailes by Sydnor, Charles Sackett
Published: Durham, NC, Duke University Press, 1938
Notes by Fries: two loose sheets of notes inserted.
I Who Should Command All, 1st edition, in honor of the opening of the Audubon Memorial Park and Museum at Henderson, Kentucky by Tyler, Mrs. Alice Jaynes
Published: New haven, Connecticut., The Framamat Publishing Co., 1937
Notes by Fries: None. Includes names of previous owners in pencil/ink
I Who Should Command All by Tyler, Mrs. Alice Jaynes
Published: New York, Putnam, 1942
Notes by Fries: None. 1st copy includes Previous owner name in ink. Second includesauthor name plate and ex libris card
NYS Library, 94th Annual Report, 1911. by University of the State of New York
Published: Albany NY, University of the State of new York, 1913
Notes by Fries: None. Ex libris card
Audubon, a vision. by Warren, Robert Penn
Published: New York, Random House, 1969
Notes by Fries: (No 88 of 300 copies signed by the author)
Birds and men; American birds in science, art, literature and conversation, 1800-1900 by Welker, Robert Henry
Published: Cambridge, Belknap Press of Harvard University Press, 1955
Notes by Fries: Letter from Case Inst. Tech. (1959) taped to front page, discussing editions of the book
Boy of the Woods; the story of John James Audubon, by Maie Lousbury Wells and Dorothy Fox, illustrated by Elinore Blaisedell by Wells, Maie Lousbury
Published: New York, Dutton, 1942
Notes by Fries: None (2nd Copy includes a Brown U lib. Card
A mirror for the sky; an opera based on an original conception of Raoul Pene du Bois for portraying the life of Audubon in a musical drama. Costume sketched by Raoul Pene du Bois by West, Jessamyn
Published: New York, Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1948
A Short history of the Winyah Historical Society of Georgetwon, South Carolina, 1755-1958, with lists of deceased and living members by Winyah Historical Society
Published: Georgetown, SC, Privately Printed by the Winyah Indgio Society, 1958
Notes by Fries: Notes on pg 3 and 36
Henderson, a guide to Audubon's home town in Kentucky, compiled by workers of the writers program of the Works projects administration in the state of Kentucky, sponsored by Susan Starling Towles by Writer's Program (U.S.) Kentucky
Published: Northport, LI, NY, Bacon, Percy and Dagget
Notes by Fries: Name of previous owners in ink. Fries' Ex libris card in copy 1, previous owner in 2.
Homes of American Authors; comprising anecdotical, personal and descriptive sketches. by Various Authors
Published: new York, Putnam; London, S. Low, Son and Co., 1852
Notes by Fries: Notes in typeface on front pages, Ex libris card
Magazines/Quarterlies/Catalogues/Exhibitions removed:
American Art in Upstate New York. Drawings, watercolours and small sculpture from public collections in Albany, Buffalo, Ithaca, Rochester, Syracuse and Utica by Albany Institute of History and Art
Published: Buffalo, NY, Buffalo Fine Arts Academy, 1974
Notes by Fries: Typewritten Sheet stapled on front cover
Art at Auction, The Year at Sptheby's and parke-Bernet, 1969-1970 by Sotheby's & Parke-Bernet
Published: New York, The Viking Press, 1971
Notes by Fries:
Museum, A Quarterly review published by UNESCO, 1952, Vol V, No.2 by UNESCO
Published: Paris, UNESCO, 1952
Notes by Fries: Includes sheets of correspondence (1969-1970) to Smithsonian Institute on "offsetting"
Art in America. Issues: April 1963, Vol 51, No.2; June 1963, Vol 51, No. 3 by Art in America Co
Published: New York, Art in America Co., 1963
Notes by Fries: vol 51 no 2: Notes on front cover, no 3: notes on front pg; both referencing relevant pg no.
American Heritage, The Magazine of History. Issues: December 1959, Vol XI No. 1 (2 copies); February 1966, Vol XVII, No. 2 by American Heritage Publishing Co
Published: New York, American Heritage Publishing Co. 1959 and 1966
Notes by Fries: Dec 1959: none. Dec 1959: typewritten note on author. Feb 1966: None
Horizon, A magazien of Arts, Spring 1966, Vol VII, No. 2 by American Heritage Publishing Co
Published: New York, American Heritage Publishing Co., 1966